Well done, well done.
You've reached the end of the section.
We've done a lot in this section.
So here's a little bit of a summary just to help you remember we started with variables.
And variables are those things that basically is an opposite of a constant.
A constant is something that can't change a variable, something that can change.
And a variable is a container where you can store something.
So if you had a variable called my variable and another section done that is basically just a container,
we've stored that piece of text or what's called a string in a variable.
And so that was the first thing we did in the importance of variables.
Then we looked at data types.
Now not all variables are created equal.
We just said for example like you don't store the turkey in the cupboard.
You don't store the car in your bookshelf.
Well, same applies to variables and data types.
So you can have a variable that is an integer like my age.
Well here we go 103.
That is an integer data type.
And you get different types of data types.
You get string data types, you get Boolean data types and a whole range of different types.
So by putting 103 in inverted commas, all of a sudden my age is actually a string.
And we looked at how important it was to be careful with your data types, especially if you start to
try and mix them.
Don't mix them.
Then we look at operators.
Operators are those little things that sit between numbers, or between variables, or even between
strings.
So we can use operators to add things, to multiply things, to divide things.
So if we had created a variable that is an integer variable called Myint and it is for, we can add
two variables together.
So we've got my age plus my int 103 plus four.
And it's 107.
We could maybe divide them.
So we remember we had the divide sign a forward slash.
And it gave us something different 25.75 and there were even others if you could remember, we had some
really funny ones that we could include that would just show you the, uh, the base of your division
and not any of the remainders and so on.
So those were operators.
Then we moved on and we looked at input.
We wanted our programs to talk to, to get us involved.
And this is where the power of programming starts to get in.
And this is where this all came together.
Because these variables are containers that has things.
But obviously we can't have the person using the program going in and changing in the code the variables.
So we want to have a prompt.
We want to ask them a question, and we want the result of their answer to that question to be stored
potentially into a variable.
So for example, if we created a variable called finished and we now wanted to ask them a question or
say to them, well done, are you happy?
Etc., we would then use the input command.
And so they would then be prompted to input.
Well done.
Are you happy?
And it could then display.
We could obviously choose to then print that variable finished.
And then it would print what was stored inside of that variable.
And so using input with variables now opens up a whole world of opportunities and possibilities.
And this is where coding really gets exciting.
So yes we are finished.
We finished the section.
Well done.
You've achieved a great next step and are now moving on to where we're going to get into some really,
really exciting stuff.
You can see the bones and the basics of your programs are coming together, but it's all about practice,
so try it for yourself over and over and over again.
Make it so it's like your second language.
And don't forget there are questions and quizzes at the end of the section, so make sure you do them.
And obviously the more you try and the more you practice, the better you will become.
And doing the questions really helps you remember and try for yourself the different things we have
been showing you.